

8+ years of QA experience in FinTech, Product Development and Information Security with a fast-paced working environment. Repeatedly recognised for being non-ordinary in a way of testing, problem solving and quality assurance, and leadership you can rely on to achieve product goals and expectations. Passionate about identifying the strengths and weaknesses of an application, validating it against the most likely functional scenarios, analysing system behaviour, and finding defects if any.

Expertise

- Agile / Bi-weekly Sprint
- Automating web services
- Rest API testing
- Unit / White box testing
- Strong Team Collaboration
- User Story Analyses
- Test Plan/Test Case
- Regression Testing
- Functional Testing
- Root Cause Analysis
- Financial Capital Market knowledge
- Software Testing Life Cycle
- Software Development Life Cycle
- Back End testing & Data Verification
- Strong Analytical & Problem-solving

Technical Skills

Platforms: Windows, UNIX/Linux, Web based, Client based, Mobile based - Android/iOS

Languages: Java, JavaScript, MySQL/SQL, HTML, CSS, API, DNS protocols, REST,

Tools: HP/ALM, Jira, Selenium, Postman, Katalon, Redmine, BrowserStack, Cypress, Jenkins,

Git, Red Hat Cygwin, Axure, Atlassian, Teams, Trello, Qase.io, Jmeter, Autocannon

Professional Experiences

A.B Digital (Korzinka) – QA Lead Engineer

Tashkent, UZ 03/2022 – 05/2023

A.B Digital is a company providing services in development of products for Web and Mobile platforms. Korzinka is the largest supermarket chain in Uzbekistan which purpose in establishing customers satisfaction and involving new features in the development and improvement of this product in a short time. As a lead, integrated a new approach to product testing. Created a knowledge base, participated in the writing and analysing product requirements, facilitate the work by introducing new tools, automation. Achieved 99.6% bug free in Firebase analytics for mobile app.

Responsibilities:

- Worked with stakeholders to ensure that the quality metrics are reviewed, closed, and agreed upon.
- Worked closely on the deadlines of the project
- Built up a team with good expertise and separated into right number and skill set of resources
- **Organised team meetings** at appropriate time to understand & review the current risks and motivate team to resolve the same.

- Implemented non-functional testing as a iterative process and trained others in using such tools
- Working closely with our PM, PO, and Dev teams to plan new features, review customer feedbacks, crash reports, and improve product user experience.
- Controlling production releases, minimising production defects cost and risks

ORIENT SWISS – QA & Integration Engineer

Tashkent, UZ 03/2021 - 03/2022

Orient Swiss introduces two products on the territory of the Silk Road. Marketplace Zoodmall and Buy Now Pay Later system Zoodpay. Both products had own API's that were integrated with partner systems, testing applications and products. Participation in the development and business team. There were debugged processes of automatisation and written technical tasks.

Responsibilities:

- Taking ownership of customer issues reported and seeing problems through to resolution
- Researching, diagnosing, troubleshooting, and identifying solutions to resolve system issues
- Following standard procedures for proper escalation of unresolved issues to the appropriate internal teams
- Helping to find out solutions for merchants in technical questions
- Testing our products for future improvement and verifying sellers' problems
- Work closely with product managers and development teams
- Support **production releases** and investigate issues

StyleMix - QA Automation Engineer

Tashkent, UZ 11/2020 – 02/2021 The

company consists of four main technology divisions: web development, mobile development. Since 2003, the company has deployed a wide range of WordPress modules and themes. There was a cooperation with the development team and management in questions of creating and maintaining automated tests as well as providing test reports on a weekly basis.

Responsibilities:

- Worked in a fast-paced **Agile/Scrum** environment.
- Ran **automation tests** for WordPress plugin on Cypress.
- Developed test plans, test cases, and test reports on multiple projects.
- Closely **collaborated** with the developer team on improving Unit testing.
- Utilised HP/ALM to organise, and manage all phases of STLC.
- Performed Functional, UI, Integration, System, and Regression testing.
- Coordinated with Dev team and BA to mitigate risks and meet release deadlines.
- Performed Backend Testing on the application to ensure **integrity of data** with database.
- Performed Root Cause Analysis to provide suggestions regarding process improvements.

The main stream of the company was applications for the personal data security and encrypted banking, cryptography, SaaS and cloud services. Mainly, focused on analyzing system behaviour under the different OS to find vulnerabilities, security checks to provide satisfactory results of safe data transferring and storing.

Responsibilities:

- REST **API Testing** (Postman)
- Testing web services, Mobile Tests, Functional Testing, Cross-Platform testing
- Stress tests, SQL injections
- Writing Test Cases
- Reporting bugs & Creating tasks in Redmine
- Test environments: Desktop OS (Win, MacOS) / Mobile (Android/iOS)

Education

Management Development Institute of Singapore in Tashkent Tashkent, UZ 09/2017 – 05/2022

Bachelor in Science

Major: Computer Information Systems for Business

Minor: IT Manager and Developer